Before I apply the wax to the face I want to test the temperature of it.
If you burn the skin on the face, if the wax is too hot, it will burn and it will scab and it will take several days to heal and sometimes scar, so you don't want to do that.
So take the time to test the temperature of the wax.
Start by dipping your stick in and if the wax, pours straight off, I'm going to do this a couple of times so you can see, if the wax pours straight off that's way too hot to go on the face.
There's no wax staying on the stick so I can't use that wax.
Another way to do that is, remember how you used to test, some people remember how you test a baby's bottle.
You touch it to the inside of your wrist.
That's too hot, you don't put that on the face.
Your face is more sensitive than any other area and the only other area that is even close to that is right here to the inside of your wrist.
So if that's too warm for there then it's definitely too warm for your face.
What you're actually looking for is the wax to be thick enough, see, to not drip off the stick.
That's the thickness that you're looking for.
If it runs off, it's too hot, sometimes the edges are a little thicker, if it doesn't run off that's ready to go, that wax is the right temperature to put on your face.
Again if you're not sure, test the wax on the inside of your wrist and I would recommend doing a test, a heat test until you're familiar with what's not too hot.
You definitely don't want to burn yourself.
So test your temperature of your wax before you touch your face.